Loren Bourassa, MBA, CPIM, CPSM

President at LRB Procurement Advisors

Summary

Proven leadership in supply chain management, including operations and procurement management consulting with over 18 years of professional experience. Broad experience in both direct and indirect procurement, with strengths including project management, procurement opportunity assessment, spend analysis, category code definition, competitive market analysis, strategic sourcing, outsourced spend management, procurement metrics design and implementation, governance, process design, organization design, commodity council design, job design, ERP and e-procurement implementations, and training development and delivery.

Experience

President

August 2008 - Present

Representative Engagement Experience:

Peoplesoft P2P Implementation Lead

- •Served as implementation lead for the Peoplesoft 9.1 eProcurement, Strategic Sourcing, and eSupplier Connect modules at a Florida-based health solutions provider with \$9.8 billion in annual revenues.
- •Led the design, configuration, and testing for all modules within scope, including the enablement of multiple punch-out catalogs, and supported Supplier Contracts module activities.
- •Developed eProcurement Requisition, Bidder Approval, Vendor Approval and Sourcing Plan workflows.
- •Created 30+ new system roles and their associated permission lists and page-level security.

Governance and Peoplesoft SRM Implementation Lead

- •Served as lead of the Governance (organization, policy, process, and metrics) track for a major procurement transformation effort at a Pittsburgh-based healthcare deliverer and insurer with \$11.9 billion in annual revenues.
- •Led the design, configuration, testing, and training of Peoplesoft eProcurement, eSettlements, Strategic Sourcing, and Services Procurement modules and multiple punch-out catalogs, and coordinated integration with the Inventory and Supplier Contracts modules
- •Developed all scripts for eProcurement, Strategic Sourcing, and Services Procurement modules and led User Acceptance Testing (UAT).

•Authored all Peoplesoft SRM module training materials and led classroom and distance-based learning sessions.

Peoplesoft SCM Implementation Architect & Lead

- •Served as functional lead for the Peoplesoft 9.2 inventory module at an Indianapolis-based integrated healthcare system with over \$16 billion in annual revenues
- •Performed all design and configuration tasks related to the Peoplesoft inventory module across multiple implementation waves
- •Developed functional inbound and outbound specifications between Peoplesoft inventory module and Cerner, Epic, QSight, SpendBridge, and Optiflex/ Omnicell applications
- Led system and User Acceptance Testing (UAT)

Senior Managing Consultant at IBM Global Services

August 2000 - August 2008 (8 years 1 month)

Responsible for the proposal, development and delivery of procurement transformation strategies and solutions that improved customers' overall operational efficiency and effectiveness. Led projects and teams with over 20 clients across a wide variety of industries, including Electronics, Healthcare, Telecommunications, Consumer Packaged Goods, Chemical & Petroleum and Entertainment.

Representative Engagement Experience:

Project Manager, Global Telecommunications Equipment Manufacturer

- Managed a major procurement transformation effort for a global telecommunications manufacturer with \$35 billion in annual revenue.
- Planned and managed a cross-functional project team with members drawn from procurement, finance, corporate IT, and logistics
- Designed and implemented a metrics system that combined internal data with external market intelligence sources to measure the competitiveness of over \$15 billion in annual direct materials spend.
- Guided the creation of an incentive program, skills assessment, educational program, and commodity team reorganization to the increase effectiveness of the client's purchasing organization.
- Achieved first-year savings of \$100M.

P2P Implementation Team Lead, Global Electronics Manufacturing Services (EMS) Provider

• Led all P2P (Procure to Pay) efforts for the roll-out of a comprehensive indirect procurement outsourcing solution that included hosted web-based purchasing and reporting tools and dedicated global sourcing, tactical buying and account payable support.

• Responsible for multiple aspects of the project including process and procedure design, vendor master definition and migration, punch-out and hosted catalog enablement, UAT testing, and training of global transactional buyers and help desk specialists in India and Hungary.

SCLP (Supply Chain Leadership Program)

May 1998 - August 2000 (2 years 4 months)

Completed IBM's prestigious two-year rotational Supply Chain Leadership Program. Led projects in a number of internal IBM Supply Chain Management groups, with a focus on procurement operations, cost modeling, market intelligence, inventory management and strategic sourcing. Received four awards for outstanding contribution while a member of IBM Integrated Supply Chain.

Representative Job Rotations:

- Technology Purchasing, Endicott, NY Special Projects Consultant
- Global Procurement Finance and Planning, Somers, NY Financial Analyst
- Manufacturing Equipment, Poughkeepsie, NY Buyer
- Software Commodity Council, Austin, TX- Council Member

Education

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid Master of Finance, Finance, 1997 - 1998 Arizona State University, W. P. Carey School of Business MBA, Business, 1996 - 1998 University of New Hampshire

BA, History, 1989 - 1994

Activities and Societies: Phi Beta Kappa, Phi Alpha Theta International Honor Society in History, Pi Gamma Mu International Honor Society in Social Science, Phi Kappa Phi Universidad Autónoma de Yucatán

Anthropology, History, 1992 - 1993

Loren Bourassa, MBA, CPIM, CPSM

President at LRB Procurement Advisors



Contact Loren on LinkedIn